Guide to the North Carolina Lesbian and Gay Health Project Records, 1983-1996 RL.00935
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- COMMUNITY CONNECTIONS SERIES
  The Community Connections Series, 1984-1995,brings together materials documenting the work of a broad range of Triangle-area and North Carolina non-profit organizations, corporations, universities, local and state commissions and agencies, and cooperative projects of those groups, primarily addressing the AIDS epidemic and/or lesbian and gay activism. The materials also document the relationships the LGHP maintained with many of those groups, sometimes including substantial participation by prominent LGHP staff members. The files include correspondence, announcements, flyers, reports, pamphlets, event programs, meeting minutes, and membership and other administrative information.
  - AIDS Action Council, 1986-1993 (Box 10)
  - AIDS Community Residence Association (Durham), 1987-1995 (Box 10)
  - AIDS Leadership: Foothills area alliance (Drexel), [1980s] (Box 10)
  - AIDS Service Agency of Wake County (Raleigh), 1990-1995, undated (Box 10)
  - AIDS Task Force of Winston-Salem, undated (Box 10)
  - Alamance Cares (Burlington), 1990's (Box 10)
  - Alternative Resources of the Triad (Greensboro), 1987-1990 (Box 10)
  - Burroughs Wellcome: HIV test advertisements--media response, 1990-1991 (Box 10)
  - Down East Pride (Greenville), 1995 (Box 10)
  - Duke University, 1989-1995, undated (Box 10)
  - Duke University AIDS Research and Treatment Center: Community Advisory Board, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Durham AIDS Network, 1989-1992, undated (Box 10)
  - Durham Area Volunteer Administrators, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Durham Human Relations Commission, undated (Box 10)
  - Family Services of Wake County, undated (Box 10)
  - Fayetteville Area AIDS Support Groups, undated (Box 10)
  - Fitts-Powell Apartments, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Gay and Lesbian Helpline of Wake County, undated (Box 10)
  - Gay and Lesbian Switchboard Conference of the Carolinas, 1994 (Box 10)
  - Funds for Families, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Gay Club (Raleigh), 1986-1988 (Box 10)
  - Eastern Regional AIDS Support and Education (Greenville), 1987 (Box 10)
  - GROW (Wilmington), 1989-1990, undated (Box 10)
  - Helpline of Wake County, 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - HIV Care Consortium, 1994 (Box 10)
  - Hospice AIDS Summit, 1994 (Box 10)
  - Human Service Alliance (Winston-Salem), 1988 (Box 10)
  - Integrity: Triangle Chapter (Raleigh), 1986-1987 (Box 10)
  - Joint Meeting of North Carolina Gay and Lesbian Health Projects, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Lambda Connection (Charlotte), 1984 (Box 10)
  - Metrolina AIDS Project (Charlotte), 1995, undated (Box 10)
  - The NAMES Project AIDS Memorial Quilt/The Triangle, 1987-1990, undated (Box 10)
  - North Carolina AIDS Services Coalition, 1988-1990 (Box 10)
  - North Carolina Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Equality, 1990-1995, undated (Box 10)
  - North Carolina Department of Environment, Health, and Natural Resources: HIV/AIDS brochure correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 10)
  - North Carolina Fair Share: Health care programming, 1988-1989 (Box 10)
  - North Carolina HIV/AIDS Alliance, 1995 (Box 10)
  - North Carolina Human Rights Fund, 1984-1991 (Box 10)
  - North Carolina Lesbian and Gay Pride, 1994 (Box 10)
  - North Carolina Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Student Organizing, 1991-1992 (Box 10)
  - North Carolina Pride PAC for Lesbian and Gay Equality, 1995 (Box 10)
  - North Carolina Royal Court (Greensboro), 1980s (Box 10)
  - Our Own Place, 1988 (Box 10)
  - Outright (Durham), 1990-1994, undated (Box 10)
  - Pitt County AIDS Service Organization (Greenville), 1993 (Box 10)
  - Tidewater AIDS Crisis Task Force, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Triad Health Project (Greensboro), 1986, undated (Box 10)
  - Triangle Cooperative AIDS Services Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 10)
  - Triangle AIDS Collaborative, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Triangle Black and White Men Together (Durham), 1989 (Box 10)
  - Triangle Men of All Colors Together (Durham), 1992 (Box 10)
  - University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 1990-1993, undated (Box 10)
  - Volunteer Center of Greater Durham, 1988-1992 (Box 10)
  - Western North Carolina AIDS Project (Asheville), undated (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous: North Carolina resources, 1980s-1990, undated (Box 10)
- SUBJECT FILES SERIES
  In the Subject Files Series, 1986-1995 and undated, the LGHP maintained extensive resource files to answer requests for information that came into their offices. Those files included pamphlets, flyers, articles, advertisements, newsletters, reports, conference proceedings, and other materials. The bulk of this series (at least 90%) documents issues related to HIV/AIDS. Materials from the resource files were regularly used in buddy and volunteer training manuals and as part of community outreach education programs. With the exception of certain reports and publications, no attempt has been made to ascertain the date of the materials in the Subject Files series.
  - Aging: Lesbians and gay men (Box 11)
  - Anti-Gay Violence (Box 11)
  - Breast Cancer (Box 11)
  - Hepatitis B (Box 11)
  - HIV/AIDS:
    - African Americans (Box 11)
    - African Americans: Gay and Bisexual Men (Box 11)
    - AID Atlanta (Box 11)
    - AIDS Action Committee (Boston) (Box 11)
    - AIDS Action Network (Box 11)
    - AIDS Volunteers of Cincinnati (Box 11)
    - Bibliographies (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Blood Donors (Box 11)
    - Caregiving (Box 11)
    - Caremark (Box 11)
    - Chemical Dependency (Box 11)
    - Children (Box 11)
    - Condoms and Dental Dams (Box 11)
    - Confidentiality issues (Box 11)
    - Disability, Social Security, and related benefits (Box 11)
    - Durham:
      - African Americans (Box 11)
      - The Care Fund (Box 11)
      - Service Providers (Box 11)
      - Statistics (Box 11)
    - Ecstasy (Box 11)
    - Education (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Ethical issues (Box 11)
    - Federal Government memoranda, miscellaneous (Box 11)
    - Hemophilia (Box 11)
    - HIV testing (Box 11)
    - HIV and health care providers (Box 11)
    - Housing (Box 11)
    - Infection Counselor Training Manual (Box 11)
    - International Conference on AIDS:
      - Amsterdam, 1992 (Box 11)
      - Berlin, 1993 (Box 11)
    - International issues (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Intravenous drug use, needle exchange, and risk reduction materials (Box 11)
    - Lesbians (Box 11)
    - Life Insurance (Box 11)
    - Living with HIV/AIDS (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Long-term survivors (Box 12)
    - Massage (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - North Carolina:
      - AIDS Resource Directory, 1989 (Box 12)
      - Confidential HIV testing (Box 12)
      - HIV Legal issue (Box 12)
      - Publications:
        - Children's Advocate, 1995 (Box 12)
        - North Carolina AIDS/HIV Update, 1989-1990 (Box 12)
        - North Carolina Update, 1992 (Box 12)
        - UNC Clinical Trials Bulletin, 1994 (Box 12)
        - The Impact of AIDS in North Carolina: A Strategic Response, 1993 (Box 12)
      - Rural issues (Box 12)
      - Sex Education legislation (Box 12)
      - Statistics (Box 12)
    - Nutrition and Food Safety (Box 12)
    - Pamphlets, miscellaneous (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - People of Color (Box 12)
    - Presidential Commission on the Human Immunodeficiency Virus Epidemic, 1987-1988 (Box 12)
    - Project Inform (Box 12)
    - Psychosocial aspects (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Publications:
      - AandU Art and Understanding, 1995 (Box 12)
      - The Active Voice, 1994-1995 (Box 12)
      - AIDS Action, 1992 (Box 12)
      - AIDS Treatment News, 1990-1992 (Box 12)
      - Being Alive, 1992 (Box 12)
      - Global AIDS Factfile, 1989 (Box 12)
      - Global AIDS News, 1995 (Box 12)
      - HIV Hotline, 1994 (Box 12)
      - HIV/AIDS Surveillance Report, 1995 (Box 12)
      - HIV Frontline, 1991 (Box 12)
      - Journal of the International Association of Physicians in AIDS Care, 1995 (Box 12)
      - Medical Alert, 1993-1995 (Box 12)
      - National Association of People with AIDS, 1986 (Box 12)
      - People with AIDS Coalition of New York Newsline, 1993-1994 (Box 12)
      - Positive Health News, 1994-1995 (Box 12)
      - Positively Aware, 1991-1995 (3 folders) (Box 12)
    - Resources, miscellaneous (Box 13)
    - Safer Sex:
      - Gay/Bisexual Men:
        - Education and risk reduction articles (2 folders) (Box 13)
        - Pamphlets (Box 13)
      - General (Box 13)
    - Sex education in schools (Box 13)
    - Southern States AIDS Education Survey [1991] (Box 13)
    - Stop AIDS Resource Center (Box 13)
    - Statistics (Box 13)
    - Stress (Box 13)
    - Transmission (Box 13)
    - Treatment issues (3 folders) (Box 13)
    - Tuberculosis (Box 13)
    - Urban issues (Box 13)
    - United for AIDS Action (Box 13)
    - Vision Disorders (Box 13)
    - Women (Box 13)
    - Youth (Box 13)
    - Youth: Gay/Lesbian/Bisexual/Transgender (Box 13)
  - Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Health Organizing (Box 13)
  - Lesbian Health (Box 13)
  - North Carolina Health Access Coalition (Box 13)
  - Prisons: Gay/Lesbian issues (Box 13)
  - Whitman-Walker Clinic (Washington) (Box 13)
  - Youth: Gay/Lesbian/Bisexual issues (Box 13)
- T-SHIRTS SERIES
  The T-Shirts Series, 1988-1995 and undated, includes t-shirts produced by the LGHP to promote the organization and its specific projects and fundraising events.
  - T-Shirts (Box 14)
- RESTRICTED MATERIALS: ADMINISTRATIVE FILES SERIES
  Closed until January 1, 2027.
  - Personnel: (Box 15)
    - Coleman, Angela, 1995 (Box 15)
    - Floyd, Keith, 1990-1991 (Box 15)
    - Harley, Carolyn, 1991-1992 (Box 15)
    - Jackson, Don, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Kirkendale, Stella, 1991-1992 (Box 15)
    - Mason, Patricia, 1993 (Box 15)
    - Millett, Gregorio, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Salak, Jerry, 1990-1991 (Box 15)
    - Warburg, Jenny, 1992, undated (Box 15)
  - Personnel Searches:
    - AIDS Educator, 1991, 1995 (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Executive Director, 1990, 1994-1995 (3 folders) (Box 15)
    - Lesbian Health Coordinator, 1995 (Box 15)
    - Volunteer Coordinator, 1991 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1989-1990 (Box 15)
- RESTRICTED MATERIALS: PROGRAMMING AND SERVICES SERIES
  - The AIDS Services Project: Buddy Program (Closed until January 1, 2027): (Box 16)
    - Client contract report, 1989-1994, undated (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Client manual, 1989-1995 (Box 16)
    - Release forms (Box 16)
  - The AIDS Services Project: Buddy Program (Open with restrictions until January 1, 2097: (Box 17)
    - Volunteer applications, 1989-1994, undated (6 folders) (Box 17)
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL
  - ADMINISTRATIVE FILES SERIES (Oversize-folder OC:V:2)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Oversize-folder OC:V:2)
  - FINANCIAL PAPERS SERIES
    - Fundraising: Triangle Gourmet Gala, 1994-95. (Oversize-folder OC:V:2)
- BANNERS SERIES, undated
  Banners used at LGHP and community events.
  - LGHP ( Lesbian and Gay Health Project) logo (Blue/Yellow) (Oversize-box 1)
  - Reducing Our Risks: Safer Sex for Gay and Bisexual Men (Yellow with Blue and Purple letters) (Oversize-box 2)
  - Triangle Bikes Against AIDS Thanks You! (Dark red with white rope; plastic slots for sponsor cards) (Oversize-box 3)
- Accession (2013-0069), 1988-1996
  - Administrative Files, Katherine Turner Files: Board Meeting Documents, 1995 (Box 18)
  - Administrative Files, Katherine Turner Files: Board Meeting Documents, 1996 (Box 18)
  - Administrative Files: Katherine Turner Board Files: Board Meeting, January 14, 1996 (Box 18)
  - Administrative Files, Katherine Turner Files: Board Member Lists, 1994-1995 (Box 18)
  - Administrative Files, Katherine Turner Files: Board Minutes & Agendas, 1994-1995 (Box 18)
  - Administrative Files, Katherine Turner Files: Budgets & Organizational Documents, 1988-1995 (Box 18)
  - Administrative Files, Katherine Turner Files: Clippings, 1995-1996 (Box 18)
  - Administrative Files: Katherine Turner Board Files, Community Forum, March 30, 1996 (Box 18)
  - Administrative Files: Katherine Turner Board Files: Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 18)
  - Administrative Files, Katherine Turner Files: Financial Documents, 1989-1995 (Box 18)
  - Administrative Files, Katherine Turner Files: Notes & Ephemera (Box 18)